So finally part two video is out.  This is
part two of the video of Tata Micare Select
Health Insurance Plan.  In this video
I will show you how all the basic things
are covered.  What are its terms and
conditions?  I am going to tell you everything inside out.
So that if you have selected this plan
or you like it.
So you can understand whether
this plan is for you or not.  So without
wasting time let's get started.  First of all, let
us talk about inpatient
treatment which is available up to 50%.
But it has some terms and
conditions.  Hospital people use two terms.  It
is important for you to understand.  One
is the Inpatient Department (IPD) which
is mentioned here and the other is the
OPD (Outpatient Department).  IPD
means that the patient gets
admitted to the hospital and takes treatment.
Outpatient means the patient comes
to the hospital but after consulting with the doctors
he goes home.
In inpatient treatment, everything
is covered for you without any limitations.  Your room
rent is covered.  Your boarding charges are
covered.  Nursing charges are also covered.
ICU ICCU everything is covered.
Doctor's fees, anesthesia, consultation
charges, specialist charges, everything
is covered for you which is also mentioned in the policy wordings.
But the problem will arise if
you have chosen a single private AC room while taking the policy
and you get admitted
in a deluxe or sweat room in the hospital.  Then the problem will arise.  Because
differential payment system is used there.
As you know, this plan
comes with an inbuilt single private AC room.
That too from the lowest category.  You
chose the same in the plan.  You did not upgrade
your room rent limit and you get admitted
in a deluxe room in the hospital.
That means
you get admitted in the category above the one for which you are eligible.  The
hospital charges for this single private room is ₹5,000.  And the
charges for the room in which you are admitted are, let's say,
₹7,000.  There is a difference of ₹2000.  There is a
difference of ₹2000 as per ₹000.
You paid Rs 20,000 less in the overall bill.  It does
n't work like that.  Because in this single private
room the nursing charges will be different.
Doctor's fees will be separate.  Operation
charges will be different.  Similarly, the
charges of nurses in deluxe or suite rooms will be
different.  Charges for diagnostic centres will be
different.  Doctors' fees, all these
things are very different.  So, you can see a
difference of Rs 2000 in the room charges also.
But, overall there is a huge
difference.  This is what we
call differential billing system.  As a
customer, you should avoid getting
admitted in a category above your room category.
Suppose by chance you have to get admitted.
You will have to pay from your pocket but
you need to understand one more thing that
differential billing system is not used in ICU
which is
clearly mentioned in their policy wordings.  Next
is pre and post hospitalization
expenses.  Here you can see 90 days pre-
hospitalization and 90 days post-
hospitalization expenses.
But there are also plans in the market
where you get post hospitalization cover up to Rs 180.
This does not mean that
you have to select that plan.  Just because it is getting
90.  Because this should
not be a selection factor.  90 Days
is Also a Good Thing.  There is nothing wrong in it.  First of all, let us
understand
what is pre and post hospitalization?  Pre-
hospitalization means that you are
admitted to the hospital.  Even before that
you might have made a lot of expenses.  Must have gone to the doctor.  Must have done
diagnostics.
Then you must have realized that a good
operation is needed.  Then you must have got admitted.
Whatever expenses are
incurred before you come to the hospital, till 90 days
before, we will call those expenses as pre-
hospitalization expenses.  That company
gives it to you but gives it in reimbursement.
Similarly, when you are discharged from the hospital
and go home, it takes
time for recovery.  Some medications are
required.  Doctor's follow ups are required.
We call all those things post
hospitalization which you experience during recovery.
You get both pre and post hospitalization expenses on reimbursement basis.  The only
condition is that you
must have the bill.  You are visiting the doctor, the
fee is Rs 1000.  The fee is Rs 2000.
Get the bill from the doctor.  Apart from that, if he prescribes any medicines,
go to the pharmacy shop and take the bill for that too. If
he prescribes any diagnostic test or
blood test,
take the bill for that too and later you
can easily apply for reimbursement. There is
a big catch here which you
need to understand.  The company says that if you have
taken the hospitalization expenses from us, that means
if we have paid the hospitalization expenses after getting admitted, then only we will give you the pre and
post hospitalization money, which is
clearly mentioned in the policy wordings.
This problem occurs to those who have
corporate insurance.  People think
that if we use corporate insurance first
and the bill is high or the
limit is exhausted then we will use our retail
insurance or personal insurance.
So he took the entire
hospitalization cost from his corporate
insurance.
When they go to claim pre and post in their personal
insurance, the company does not pay.
Why?  Because the company rules are that
unless you take the hospitalization bill from us,
we will not give you pre and post.
Even if you were admitted legally or lawfully,
you will still not give it.  So
what you have to do in this is that whatever
corporate insurance you use,
you should take corporate insurance for 90% of the bill.
You leave 10%.  Inpatient that means
leave the hospital bill.  Claim that 10% from your personal
insurance and for that reason
your personal insurance company will give you pre and post as well.
So
you need to take some money in patient and
else your pre and post will be lost and you will
not be eligible.  This is
clearly mentioned in the terms and conditions.  Next
is day care procedure.  All day care
treatments are covered here up to Rs. 1000.
That means there are no limits of any kind here.
None are listed here.  That
means any hospitalization that lasts
less than 24 hours falls under day care.
Like you have had chemotherapy,
you have had minor surgeries or you have had
radiotherapy.  All these things
take less than 24 hours or dialysis is done.
This kind of thing comes up in day care.
All those things are covered without any
limitations.  Next is organ donor
coverage.  This is also covered up to some and shot.  It sounds
very nice.  But
listen to the terms and conditions.  If the other
person or someone from your family is
donating to you, then only the expenses incurred
in removing any organ from the other member are
covered.  That too on
transplant day, many tests are done before that also.
Like there is a matching
test.  DNA is
all the things that match.  Whether the donor is fit or
not.  There are two-four donors, who among them
is fit?  Who is not fit?  Whatever
expenses are incurred in the tests, all those things will
not be available to the donor.  Which
is clearly mentioned in the terms and conditions.  What
is covered?  Only your harvesting cost
is covered.  That means on the day of organ transplant,
whatever time is required to remove that part and
whatever expenses are going to be incurred in putting it inside me, all those
things are covered.
Apart from this, what is happening to the donor, what is not
happening, whether any complication is coming or not
, all these things are not covered for the donor.
Suppose the donor faces any complication during the
operation, then all those
things which are clearly mentioned in the terms and conditions are not covered.
And it is standard in the insurance
industry that no one covers a donor for more.
Except the harvesting cost.  But there
are some companies in the market which
also cover the risk of the donor.  Suppose any
complication arises, it covers that too.
So, if you have any such
requirement, then this plan is not
for you.  Next is domiciliary treatment.
This is also covered up to some in shots.  But it has
very strict guidelines which
you need to understand.  It had become very
common.  When there was Corona,
beds were not available in hospitals.  Then
it could have come in handy.  But one thing to note is
that even during Corona, every company had
imposed a limit on trading Corona.
So in situations like pandemic, the
company makes its own separate guidelines.  He
comes only then.  For now we are
going to assume that up to this amount is covered.   There
are certain criteria for domiciliary hospitalization that you
need to follow.  If you have a patient or are
unable to go to the hospital due to some
illness or injury, you
can choose domiciliary hospitalization.  Or if you
want to go to the hospital but there are
no beds available in the hospital, then you are still
eligible for domiciliary hospitalization.  The
condition for the claim to be approved is
that your domiciliary hospitalization must
last for at least three days.  Three or
more days.  The second condition is
that you have taken domiciliary hospitalization for some illness only.
Suppose
you are looking for a condition in which your
parents are in the last stage and are
facing some feeding problem or some
end of life support problem.  For
that reason, you called nurses to your home saying
that he
needs hospitalization.  I am not able to eat this.  I am not able to do this
, I am not able to do that.  If
you do this for some such things then you will not get the money
which is clearly mentioned in the terms and conditions.
And the most important thing is that you must have a
return certificate from the doctor that
your hospitalization must be in the form of domicile.  Only then will
you
get the claim.  The company has written
that it is covered up to sum and shsh.
Also promotes that up to some in and
short is covered.  But as a customer, you will get the claim only if
you follow these strict guidelines.
Else your
claim will get denied.  Next is Ayush
benefit.  Up to some is covered.
For AYUSH treatment also, you get pre and post
hospitalization coverage
without any limitations.  Before getting
admitted for AYUSH treatment.  Just remember one thing
that the hospital you are going to
should be registered and on top
of that, it is necessary for those hospitals to follow all the benchmarks of the government.
Next is ambulance coverage.  Up
to some shots are covered.  But brother, this also has
terms and conditions.  The first term
and condition is that the ambulance coverage should be within
50 km.  It will work only within a radius of .
From the injury area or from home.
Now see where it will work.
From the site of emergency to the nearest
hospital.  Second from home to the hospital.
If medically necessary, then from one
hospital to another hospital for better
treatment.  Or from hospital to
home.  If prescribed by the doctor, the
ambulance is covered up to sum and shot.
And people think that you can
take an ambulance in any situation.  So it is
not like that.  The situation should be life threatening
or should be accident related.  Only then
you get the money for the ambulance.  There
is a gas problem.  You fell down
, fainted.  Something like this happened and
your family was in a very emergency
situation.  You went to the hospital.  There I came to know
that there was no emergency at all.
So you will not get money for that thing.  I am
enjoying the video so far, please
like it.  Because many people do
n't like it.  And this video does
not go into the suggestion box for many people.  And if you
want to take any plan,
I have given a policy link in the market.   There
is an affiliate link.  If you take any plan from there,
this channel gets help.  So
go and check in once.  As soon as
you enter your number there, you will get a
call from the company.  The entire plan will be explained to you in
detail.  If you like it then take it.  If
they don't like it then there
is no compulsion.  Next is Restoration
Infinity Plus Unlimited Times in a
Policy Year.  Many people have this doubt that
Sir, if there is unlimited restoration then the
plan of ₹1 lakh will reach up to 1 crore.
Yes, it will reach.  But
you can't deliver in one hospitalization.
Because a maximum of ₹1 lakh will be restored in one hospitalization.
For example,
your coverage is ₹1 lakh.  Here is your ₹1
lakh, you have used 10% from here.  That
means ₹1 lakh was used.
This ₹1 lakh that you used in the next hospitalization
, it gets refilled because the
utilized amount itself is ₹1 lakh
, so only that much will be refilled.  If you
utilize it 100% then the company will
give you 100% up to ₹1 lakh next time.  But it does not spend more than ₹1 lakh for
one hospitalization.  Yes, if
you have fully utilized 50% in any hospitalization, the
company will
restore the remaining 50% in your next hospitalization.
So this is how Unlimited
Restoration works.
If I tell you in one sentence then restoration is
unlimited times.  This will
work for both related and unrelated accounts and
your restoration will be activated even on partial utilization.  That means whatever is
required is provided in this plan.
Unbiased Ram Singh This
channel is unbiased because
I am not directly affiliated with any company
or no company has given me money to
make this video.  So
if you want to support the channel and
were planning to buy a plan from Policy Bazaar,
then go to the link below in the description
box and register from there.
This channel needs a lot of help so that
more content like this keeps coming.
Next is daily cash for choosing twin
sharing or multi sharing accommodation.
Here, if you choose twin sharing
for admission, you get ₹1200
per day.  And if you
choose multi sharing then you
get extra money at the rate of ₹1500 per day.  There are
some conditions, understand that also.  This will be
available only to those who were eligible for single private
AC room or above category.
And they chose whether I wanted to be
admitted in a sharing room or a multi-sharing room.   Only
they will get this money.  If you had
chosen twin sharing at the time of taking the policy, then
you will not get the money because you were
eligible for that category.  The
company gives this because you are saving the company's money.  If
you were eligible
for a single private AC room or a deluxe
room, then your money
goes to the hospital for treatment.
Because you saved the company's money, the
company is compensating you.  Giving
you a little privilege in the form of extra money.
So both of them benefit.  In
this way, after completion of every 24 hours,
your one day will be considered.
Accordingly, you will be given money according to the number of days you were admitted.
The
best thing is that if you utilize this thing
then it will not affect your no claim bonus.
I am going to tell you further how to get No Claim Bonus.
Next is No Claim
Bonus.  Here the company gives you 50% extra
coverage.  Up
to a maximum of 100% if you do not claim.  If you have insurance of ₹1 lakh.
You did not claim for the entire year.
You will definitely get insurance of ₹1 lakh at the time of renewal.
Apart from that, you will be given an extra coverage of ₹5 lakh
as a no claim bonus.  You did
not claim the next year also.  You will be
given an extra bonus of ₹5 lakh.  So in this way
your no claim bonus will keep increasing.
How much will the maximum increase be?  Maximum increase up to 100%.
If you are in this situation and
you have made a claim, then at the time of renewal
you will not get the bonus
because you have made a claim.  Apart from that,
your bonus will be reduced and it will become
zero.  So in the same way, if you
are in this scenario and you have taken a claim in this scenario, then at the
time of renewal your
₹1 lakh will be refreshed.  From here your
50% bonus will be minus.  That
means you will have the same amount of coverage after renewal.
So this is how their no
claim bonus works.  Next is the room
category.  I don't know
why he gave it so low?  Because the room category always
comes written on top of every brush.  There
is a single private AC room here.  If you
look at the terms and conditions wordings, the
company has clearly mentioned it.  Single
Private AC Room means that
you will be eligible for the lowest category single private AC room with attached bathroom in the hospital.
So you need to understand.  Here
you are also given the option of upgrade.
So if you upgrade, you
come to no room rent limit.  So if you
want a little discount then you are
also given the option of downgrade here.
Finally, I have explained all the basic features of this plan
in detail.
And if you liked the video then please
like it and if you have any doubts or questions
or queries then let
me know in the comment section below.  You will
get a reply within 24 hours.
Part three is also coming because I
want to make the video slowly.
So that you understand everything.
Or if you think that no friend,
I want to know everything in one video, then
tell me that also.  I will make the video in the same manner from next time.
I had come to my village
and I thought that the video is
coming very late so I should make it.
I am making it sitting in my small garden.
If you look, the farm
is there.  And This Is the House.  So, friend,
please like the video.